来我身边
Come to me.
守护天使也好
A guardian angel.
抚慰之灵也罢
A spirit of comfort.
来自任何天界的神灵
Spirit of any celestial sphere.
谁都可以
Anything.
请听我的召唤
Hear my call.
来我身边
Come to me.
你
你将我从永恒的黑暗中唤醒
你...你...
你不属于人世间
你非人类所能触及
你愿意与我永世共存吗？
你愿以此起誓吗？
我发誓
l swear.
托马斯
Thomas.
Thomas?
什么事 亲爱的
What's that, my love?
你怎么了
What is it?
没事 我只是
Nothing. l
我梦见...我...
I dreamt...l
过来
Come here.
没什么好担忧的 好吗
There's nothing to be afraid of, hmm?
蜜月结束得实在太早
The honeymoon was yet too short.
把鞋脱掉
Take off your shoes.
我也想留下来陪你 亲爱的
I wish I could stay, my love.
我何德何能娶到你这么好的老婆
How should I have earned such a doting wife?
爱伦
Ellen.
我说过别让她上床
I told you not to let her into bed.
我身上所有衣服都粘了它的毛
Everything I wear, absolutely covered in it.
可格蕾塔喜欢这里
But Greta loves it here.
她也希望你别走
She wishes you to stay, too.
今天是我们的大日子
Today is of the utmost importance for us.
再待一分钟就好
One minute more.
我必须得走了
I really must be off.
再见
Goodbye.
他已经得到了那份工作
He has the position already.
他们会派他去远行
They'll send him away.
早安
Morning.
让一让
Excuse me.
你耽误了他一刻钟
You have kept him a quarter hour.
抱歉 先生
Forgive me, sir.
请原谅 诺克先生
Pray, pardon me, Herr Knock,
我迟到了
for my tardiness.
你的迟到都是天意 孩子 天意
Your delay is providential, my boy, providential.
请进
Come in, come in.
我还在收拾账目
Still preparing the account.
多谢您可以考虑我 先生
Uh, and I thank you, sir, for considering me.
当我得知你刚刚成家的消息后
When tidings of your recent nuptials reached my ears,
我就知道这都是天意
I knew it was providence.
一个新郎官需要一份新工资
A new husband requires new wages.
您真慷慨 先生
You're too generous, sir.
请允许我向你的妻子道声恭喜
Allow me to extend my congratulations to your wife.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
她真是个美人
She truly is beautiful.
一个人间尤物
A...a nonpareil.
简直是个
Almost a
窈窕仙女
sylph.
是的 多谢夸奖 先生
Yes. Thank you, sir.
无论您有什么要求
Uh, and I'm most eager to proceed
我都非常乐意去做
with whatever your request,
这样我也可以全身心地投入公司业务中
that I might be fully engaged with the firm.
是啊 是啊
lndeed, indeed.
都是天意
Providence.
我目前正和一位外国伯爵谈生意
Now, I have been entertaining dealings with a foreign count.
非常古老的贵族血脉
Very old line of nobility.
岁数很大而且...很古怪
Very old and...eccentric.
他希望可以在威斯堡这里安家
He wishes to acquire a home here in our Wisburg.
-是吗 -在这颐养天年
Oh, yes? - To retire here.
可以说 他已经是一只脚进棺材的人了
He has one foot in the grave, so to speak.
呃 我很乐意陪同这位先生
Uh, I should be pleased to escort the gentleman
并将我们的房产推荐给他
and recommend him to our properties.
我已经挑选了格吕内瓦尔德庄园
I have already selected Grunewald Manor.
恕我冒昧 先生 可那里不是废墟吗
Forgive me, sir, but is it not, well, uh, a ruin?
是他执意要求找老房子
He requested an old home,
而且他愿意为此一掷千金
and he will pay most generously.
那我明天上午接待他 九点钟可以吗？
I shall meet him tomorrow, then- - nine of the clock?
问题就出在这里
Here is the peculiarity.
他过于孱弱不能长途旅行
He's too infirm to travel,
所以你必须亲自去拜会他
so you needs must journey to him.
我明白了
l see.
他住在波希米亚东部的一个小国家
He lives in a small country east of Bohemia,
在喀尔巴阡山脉深处与世隔绝
isolated in the Carpathian Alps.
这将是场伟大的冒险孩子
lt will be a great adventure, my boy.
的确
lndeed.
不能等伯爵来这里之后再签约吗
Uh, may not the count execute the deed here when he arrives?
噢 不行 这单子很急
Oh, no, it is much too urgent.
他坚持让我们派一名代理人过去
He insists we offer him an agent
要活蹦乱跳的
in the flesh.
他会给你丰厚的报酬 孩子 非常丰厚
And he will reward you handsomely, my boy, handsomely.
保住这名客户 就能保住你在
Secure this account, and you will secure your...
这间公司的正式职位
official position in the firm.
谢谢 先生 十分感谢
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
我不会让您失望
I shan't disappoint.
请问那位伯爵尊姓大名？
And what was the count's name?
奥洛克
Orlok.
我明天就得出发
And I shall have to set off tomorrow,
因为旅程要六星期
as it is a six- week journey.
不过哈玎已经好心答应我
But 德语ing has generously agreed
在我回来以前照顾你
to keep you till my return.
为什么要杀死这些美丽的花朵
Why have you killed these beautiful flowers?
-什么 -没事
What? - Nothing.
-你说什么 -原谅我
What are you talking about? - Forgive me.
我们把花插进水里吧
Uh, let us put them in water.
反正它们没几天就会死
They will only die in a few days.
-扔了吧 -什么
Throw them out. - What?
把它们扔掉
Throw them outl
你怎么了…
What are you.
你不能去
You cannot leave.
你这是怎么了
What is this?
我必须告诉你我梦见了什么
I must tell you my dream.
爱伦 我们已经战胜了那些困难
Ellen, we have put these difficulties behind us.
-我必须说 -求你了
- I must. Please.
不要再纠结你的那些儿时回忆了
No more of your childhood memories.
-医生说过永远别去回想... -不
The doctors advised never No.
我梦见我们的婚礼
lt was our wedding.
但不是身处在教堂
Yet not in chapel walls.
头顶上是密不透风的乌云
Above was an impenetrable thundercloud
一直延伸到山外
outstretched beyond the hills.
暴雨中传来一阵阵浓烈的丁香花气息…
The scent of the lilacs was strong in the rain, and...
当我走到圣坛前...
when I reached the altar.
你却不在那里
...you weren't there.
我面前站的 一袭黑衣
Standing before me, all in black,
那是…
was...
死神
Death.
可我却满心欢喜
But I was so happy.
充满了喜悦
So very happy.
我们交换誓言 彼此拥抱
We exchanged vows, we embraced,
当我们转过身
and when we turned around,
所有人都死了
everyone was dead.
我父亲还有...每一个人
Father and...everyone.
他们的尸臭味是那般恐怖
The stench of their bodies was horrible.
而且…
And.
可我从未那般幸福过
But I'd never been so happy
在那一刻
as that moment.
我与死神手牵着手…
...as I held hands with Death.
千万别把这件事声张出去
Never speak these things aloud.
永远不要
Never.
不过是个无关紧要的愚蠢恶梦
lt is a trifle, a foolish dream,
和你过去的那些幻想一样
just as your past fancies.
一切都平安无事
Everything is well.
这对我们来说是个不祥的预兆
lt portends something awful for us.
听着 等我回来
Look, when I return,
我就终于可以出人头地了
I will finally make something of myself.
我要给咱们买座带佣人的漂亮大宅
I shall buy us a fine house of our own with a maidservant...
我们不需要那些
We needn't any of that.
我希望你能得到应得的一切
I wish you to have all you deserve.
你不能走 我太爱你了
You mustn't leave. I love you too much.
拜托 别说了
Pray, stop.
自我们学生时代就没有过 汤姆
Never since our school days, Tom.
-这是我祖父留下的佳酿 -噢 我不能
From my grandfather, the best. - Uh, uh, no, I oughtn't.
你的冒险值得庆祝一番
Uh, it's worth celebrating your adventure.
谢谢
Thank you.
-我真羡慕你 -嗯
- Ienvy you. Mm.
我羡慕你才对
I- l envy you.
你现在是真的取代了你父亲的位置
You've truly taken your father's place now.
很不可思议
lt's incredible.
这该死的责任 真的太沉重了 托马斯 真的
The bloody responsibility, it's crushing, Thomas, crushing.
当然 我这样抱怨也是很不得体的
Of course, it's unseemly to complain
毕竟也有这么多的收入了 但是市场的需求
with all the earnings, but the demands of the market
比船厂的增长快多了
grow faster than the damned shipyard.
我还有两个女儿呢 两个啊 汤姆
And my two girls- two, Tom.
这个世界上没什么比她们更重要的
I...I love them more than the world.
但是别跟爱伦
And speak none of this to Ellen
还有安娜说这些 我们又要有一个孩子了
or my Anna, but we have another on the way.
-没错 -恭喜了
Mm- hmm. Congratulations.
毕竟你总是像头发情的山羊
Hey, you always were a rutting goat.
我真的抗拒不了她
- I cannot resist her.
你们两个什么时候要啊
And when will you two newlyweds?
等我有钱了的时候吧
When I'm no longer a pauper.
费德里希 我说真的 等我有钱了的时候
Uh, Friedrich, when I have, I mean to say,
我会把你借我的钱
I shall finally be able to return
-全部都还给你的 -别再说了
the moneys you loaned me. Not another word.
-嗯 对了 费德里希 -怎么了
Uh, and, Friedrich? - Hmm?
一定要照顾好爱伦
Do take care of Ellen.
她几乎是求着我留在这里
She nearly begged me to remain here.
让你放弃大好的机会吗
And toss aside your fine opportunity?
我很担心她过去的忧郁症复发
I fear her past, uh, melancholy returning.
也是当然 毕竟她年轻英俊的丈夫
Naturally. Her dashing young husband's
要离开她的床笫了
leaving her bedside cold.
睡觉时间到了 不要闹哕
My sweet ones, it's time now for bed.
爸爸 爸爸
Papal Papal
不
No!
乖 听你们妈妈的话
Listen, then, to your mother.
时间已经到了 已经可以了
The time has simply come. Enough now.
-好了 可以了 -来吧
Come on. All right. Come.
不要 房间里有只怪物
We can'tl There is a monster in the room!
爸爸 爸爸
Papa! Papa!
别让她把我喂给那只怪物
Don't let her feed me to the monster.
捅死他
Stab him!
失陪 我要动身去猎杀怪物了
Pardon us, but I am to hunt a monster.
你也幼稚得像个小孩
You're a perfect child yourself.
-晚安 -晚安
Good night. Good night.
上楼吧 来吧
Up we go. Come
爸爸 陪着我们别走！
Papa, please stay with us!
等你们睡熟了我再走
I will stay with you until you are fast asleep.
我能听到他在床下呼吸的声音
I can hear him breathing beneath my bed!
胡说什么呢 亲爱的 这里很安全
Nonsense, my darling. You are safe and sound.
原谅我
Forgive me.
我已经把这些幻想抛之脑后了
I have put these fancies behind me.
真的
l have.
我们还有彼此
And we have each other.
大人 这都是完全按照您的要求来的
Your lordship, it is entirely as you have demanded.
他马上就会臣服于你
He shall presently be in thy rule,
而我将会在此侍奉您左右
and I shall attend thee here,
就在您购置的土地上
near the object of thy contractl
-我为你感到骄傲 -嗯
I'm proud of you. - Mm.
一定要小心
Please keep safe.
你就对我这么没有信心吗
Have you so little faith in me?
我会全心全意地相信你
I will send you my utmost faith.
而你要每天给我写信
And you will write to me every day.
我会的 我保证
Ishall. Ipromise.
记住 这全都是为了我们
Remember, it's all for us.
-我爱你 -我爱你
- Ilove you. l love you.
再会
Farewell.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了
Okay.
我真的很抱歉 真的
I'm sorry. Sorry, no
吵吵嚷嚷的是在干什么
滚出去 肮脏的吉普赛人
你们玷污了我的旅馆
你给我惹来了麻烦
请原谅 我只想留宿一夜
Uh, forgive me. I- I only wish to stay one night.
城堡里有人在等我前往
I have an audience at the castle.
就是阿尔涅克隘口外的奥洛克城堡
Castle Orlok, beyond the Arnyek Pass
看在上帝的份上 别提那名字
回到你的国家去 外乡人
闭嘴
愿上帝的圣灵驱逐你
我真的很累 求求您
I am weary, l- l pray you.
走吧
Go.
我可以付双倍的钱
I will pay double the board.
吾将你驱逐 用大蒜将你驱逐
拜托 拜托请不要去那里
要当心他的阴影
那阴影会将你笼罩在噩梦之中
清醒着 但依然在梦里
无从脱逃
祈祷吧
祈祷吧 祈祷吧
保佑这位年轻的处女
保佑她吧
指引我们的种马找到不洁之灵
是吸血鬼！
是吸血鬼的坟墓！
找到他的兽尾
他那不分趾的蹄子
安静
上帝让你毁灭
不 看在上帝的份上
No, by the grace of Godl
有人吗
Hello?
我的马呢
My horse?
你来迟了
You are late.
午夜已经过了
The midnight hour has passed.
我的侍从都已经休息了
And my attendants have all retired.
请原谅 伯爵大人
Forgive me, Count.
请你随意
Leave there your conveniences.
拿出地契 坐下
Set out the deed and sit.
您不希望等到明天早上吗？
Would you not wish to wait til morning?
我希望你按照我说的做
I wish you to do as I request.
好的
Yes.
当然了 先生
Of course, sir.
大人
Lord.
您说什么 先生？
Pardon me, sir?
称我为”大人”
Your lord.
我的称呼
I will be addressed
必须与我血脉的荣耀相符
as the honor of my blood demands it.
是的 大人
Yes, my lord.
请原谅 大人
Forgive me, my lord.
请你...
Pray...
坐吧
sit.
谢谢您 大人
Thank you, my lord.
我已经迫不及待
I am most impatient
想要看到你的地契合同
to bring my eyes on your covenant papers.
还有我和
And my correspondence
你的雇主 诺克先生的通信
with your proprietor, Herr Knock.
我已经等很久了
I have long awaited them.
这是自然 大人
Of course, my lord.
喝
Drink.
我...大人 我有些疑问
I have, my lord...uh, l have questions
是关于一些 我不熟悉的民俗
about the, um, unfamiliar customs of the peasantry
还有那些流浪者
and the errant wanderers.
昨天晚上 我看见了…
Last night, I saw
或者是 我认为我看到了 一群吉普赛人
or, rather, I believe I saw a band of gypsies.
他们进入了一小片白桦林 然后...
They ventured to a small birch grove and.
恐怕我们这里还保留着
I fear we yet keep close
许多封建迷信
many superstitions here
在你这样学识渊博的年轻人看来
that may seem backward
是十分愚昧落后的
to a young man of your high learning.
这些吉普赛人挖出了一具尸体
These gypsies, they exhumed a corpse.
这是他们肮脏的仪式
lt is their filthy ritual.
究竟是什么样的仪式…
What manner of ritual
不要再提了
Speak not of it againl
我很期待去到你们那
How I look forward to retiring
充满现代思想的城市安度晚年
to your city of a modern mind.
那里没有人听说过
...who knows nothing of
也不相信这些病态的童话传说
nor believes any such morbid fairy tales.
吃吧
Eat.
你结婚了吗 哈特先生
You are married, Herr Hutter?
注意你的举止
Take heed what you do.
小伤罢了
lt's nothing.
我也许能疗愈你的伤口
I might ease your wound.
来炉火这边
Come by the fire.
看脸色你一定不舒服
Your face shows you unwell.
等我一下
Wait for mel
小心孩子们
Careful, children.
远离那些脏污
Keep from that filth.
来抓我呀
Catch mel
有的时候你会不会觉得自己
Do you ever feel at times as if you were not
仿佛不像是个人
as if you were not a person?
-这 我... -我的意思是
Well, I What I wish to say is that
仿佛你不是真正地存在或者活着
you are not truly present nor alive,
仿佛你一直在受某人摆布 像个洋娃娃
as if you were at the whim of another, like a doll,
某个人或者是什么东西有这种魔力
and someone or something had the power
能给你注入生命
to breathe life into you,
让你像活人一样动起来
to move you.
当然 我们有时都会觉得不舒服
Well, of course we all feel out of sorts at times.
这不是舒不舒服的问题 更像是...
lt's not out of sorts. lt's...it's as if there is
有别的什么在作祟 但过于可怕而无法解释
something at play that is too awful or grave to explain.
-是上帝吧 -不 我亲爱的安娜
God. No, my lovely Anna.
我...
I...
看看天空 还有海洋
Look at the sky. Look at the sea.
你从来没感受过它们呼唤你 催促你吗？
Does it never call to you, urge you?
某些近在咫尺的东西
Something is close at hand.
那就是他的力量
That is his power.
从天堂吹来的和风
A gentle breeze from heaven.
是命运！
Destiny!
我亲爱的浪漫人儿
My sweet romantic.
我没有生气 安娜
I am not mad, Anna.
伦儿
Leni.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
我说的话 听起来都好幼稚
Everything I say sounds so childish.
你说的话 都出自你的真心
Your words spring from your honest heart.
托马斯不在 我的心也迷失了
My heart is lost without my Thomas.
有人吗？
Hello?
伯爵？
Count?
这还需要作为律师的
And your signature
你的签名
as solicitor.
我真是太粗心了 大人
How careless of me, my lord.
这是我先祖的文字
The language of my forefathers.
原来如此
Of course.
这是 一个少女的信物
A maiden's token, I see.
你的新娘？
Your bride?
是的 它 呃...
Just so. lt, uh
确实如此
Yes.
我能看看吗？
May l?
我们最近才刚结婚
We are newly married of late.
顺带一提 如果可以的话
lncidentally, I have letters to her
我有封信要寄给她
I would post, if I may.
薰衣草香
您说什么 大人？
What was that, my lord?
你很幸运能得到真爱
You are fortunate in your love.
正如诺克先生所说 这是天意
lt's providence, as Herr Knock would say.
你的签名
Your signature.
我希望...
I pray...
你能谅解我
you will indulge my pardon.
我绝没有轻视你的委托
I durst not neglect your commission.
哈特先生
Herr Hutter.
现在我们是邻居了
Now are we neighbors.
这是我的荣幸 大人
lt is my good fortune, my lord.
请原谅我这样问 大人
Forgive my asking, my lord,
但为什么选择格吕内瓦尔德庄园这样的古宅呢？
but why such an antique residence as Grunewald Manor?
契约已经签好了
The covenant is signed.
当然
Of course.
那么 我诚挚地恭喜您
Well, I thank you and congratulate you
即将乔迁新居
on your new home.
已经很晚了
lt is late.
你肯定想休息了吧
You must wish to retire.
如果我可以的话 大人
lfImay, my lord,
我这样说可能有些冒犯
i- if I may be slightly unsubtle in my approach,
我 我就是希望尽快能
I- I wish to depart as soon as
这个 能在我在完成为您的服务以后立即启程
well, as soon as agreeable my services rendered.
我有点…
I am much...
最近我一直在受离奇古怪的梦境折磨
I have been enduring the most irregular dreams.
恐怕我生病了
I fear I am taken ill.
若身体健康不佳 则不宜出门远行
lt is a black omen to journey in poor health.
你应该留下来好好休息
You will remain and well rest yourself.
恕难从命 大人
Uh, Imust object, my lord.
你会照做的 我的律师
You will obey this, my counsel.
但是大人…
Uh, but, my lord
伯爵？
Count?
我的吊坠还在你那
Y- You have my locket.
你的丈夫已不再与你同在
梦见我
唯有我
这是一种轻度的梦游症
ln mild cases of somnambulism- sleepwalking-
它是由于血液淤积引发的
it is brought on by a congestion of the blood.
就是血液过多
Too much blood.
也许 她是身体受到了压迫
Perhaps perhaps she was oppressed
睡姿有点奇怪之类的
in a somewhat odd position beforehand.
但是 她过去也有过同样的经历
Yet she has had these fits in the past.
-神经紧张等等 -这样啊
Troubled nerves and so on. - l see.
如果症状继续下去 请告诉我 但在那之前
Well, if it continues, let me know, but until then,
亲爱的朋友 不用太担心
uh, keep it from your worries, my dear fellow.
好的 当然
Yes, of course.
我倾向于建议她穿束身胸衣睡觉
I am disposed to recommend that she sleep in her corset.
这能让身体保持正确的姿势
lt encourages correct posture,
镇静子宫 恢复血液循环
calms the womb and revives circulation.
好的 那太好了
Yes, very well.
而且 如果她的情绪波动严重
And, uh, if her stirring escalates,
你也可以把她绑在床上
you can always tie her to the bed.
噢 他来找我了
Oh, he's coming to me.
他要来了
He's coming.
我会增加乙醚的用量
I'll increase the ether.
没有托马斯的信？什么都没有？
Nothing of Thomas? Nothing?
是的 我是说 我什么都没收到
No. Imean, yes, I've received nothing of any kind.
甚至连你的船厂...也没有吗？
Not even to your...at the shipyard?
那诺克先生呢？
And Herr Knock?
仍然没有发现他的踪迹
Still no trace of him.
他的公司每天都处于混乱之中
His firm is in daily chaos.
我从来都不喜欢那个人
I never liked that man. Never.
我会亲自去他办公室直接找他
I shall call upon his office myself directly.
-拜托 哈特夫人 别这样 -我总得知道些什么
Please, Frau Hutter, no. l must discover something.
-噢 看在上帝的份上 -但是托马斯
Oh, for heaven's sakel But Thomas
你不能单独离开
You cannot leave unaccompanied.
我很理解你急切的心情
I am most sensitive to your ardent nature
也不会因为你错误的判断 对你多加责怪
and shan't reprove you further in this error of judgment.
我会每天派人 直到找到诺克先生
I will send someone daily until Herr Knock is found.
托马斯很好
Thomas is well.
我很确信
l'm certain of it.
伦儿 快日落了
Leni, it's near sundown.
我们真的应该走了
We really ought to be leaving.
伦儿？
Leni?
再等一会儿
Just a moment longer.
拜托
Please.
费德里希 拜托别这么小气
Friedrich, be not a churl, please.
你不该被她的神经质所迷惑
You mustn't be swept up in her fairy ways.
全家现在都围着她为中心团团转
The entirety of the household centers upon her whims.
我已经不想在说她了
I tire of discussing her.
你以为这对我来说就不沉重吗？
Think you there is no burden upon myself?
我爱她
I love her.
她的病并不是她的错
She is blameless for her malady.
原谅我 亲爱的
Forgive me, my love.
西弗斯医生会再来为她看诊的
Dr. Sievers will pay her another visit.
求求你 让我们聊点别的吧
Let us only please talk of something else.
我们的小费德里希怎么样了？
How is our little Friedrich, hmm?
好吧 像往常一样饿得快
Well, hungry as always.
就像他的父亲一样
Like his father. - Mm.
费德里希 光天化日的
Friedrich, in public?
我没法抗拒你 亲爱的
I cannot resist you, my love.
爱伦？
Ellen?
伦儿！
Leni!
新病人吗？
New patient?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
呃 我们把他关在楼下了 先生
Uh, we stowed him downstairs, sir.
我严令禁止过使用旧的病房
I have strictly forbidden the use of the old cells.
-对不起 先生 -这绝对不可以
Begging your pardon, sir. lt's out of the question.
这是一所现代化的医院 不是监狱
This is a modern hospital, not a prison.
他虽然看着一把老骨头 但在我看来
A little old soul he may look, but on my life,
见过了他的尖叫 他的呻吟
saw him screaming and a- groaning.
在路德圣诞市场找到他时
Found him at the Luther Christmas Market.
他徒手杀死了三只羊
Killed three sheep with his bare hands.
他像野兽一样生吃了它们
And he was eating them raw- like.
生吞活剥！
Raw!
日安 先生
Good day, mein Herr.
我是西弗斯医生
I am Dr. Sievers.
有什么问题吗？
What seems to be the trouble?
没问题
No trouble.
天意呀！天意呀！
Providence. Providence.
这样啊
l see.
先生 你能告诉我你的名字吗？
Can you tell me your name, Herr...?
我没有名字
I am no one.
我是他的仆从
I am his servant.
那么 你这些都是什么？
And, um, what do you have there?
生命 恩赐
Lives, gifts,
这都是大人他赐予我的
bestowed upon me by his lordship.
看 这个很漂亮
Look, this is a pretty one.
大人他喜欢漂亮的
His lordship likes the pretty ones
最好的…
best.
大人？
His lordship?
他即无限
He is infinity.
双眼闪 着精光
Eyes shining
好似镶满珠宝的王冠
like a jeweled diadem.
然后是腐化败烂
And then putrescence.
窒息
Asphyxience.
最终吞噬殆尽
And devourence.
我的好伙计 你这样是为何？
Now, my good fellow, why would you do that?
没关系的
lt's all right.
没有人想伤害你 亲爱的朋友
No one wants to hurt you, my dear friend.
他要来了
He is coming.
谁？
Who?
谁要来了？
Who is?
是他召唤了我
Twas he that invoked me.
是我被选中侍奉他
Twas I that was chosen to serve him,
因为我深知他觊觎何物
for I know what he covets.
他将施加于尔等
And he shall cast upon you
诅咒 扰乱 苦难 斥责
curses, confusion, afflictions, rebukes,
因为尔等弃我而去
for you have forsaken me,
他将统治天下
and he shall reign over
立于尔等空洞的尸身之上
all of your empty corpses.
吞噬殆尽
Devourence.
Devourence!
哈玎 来帮我
德语ing, help me
她这些歇斯底里之症一到夜晚
These hysterical spells come over her at nightfall
就准时发作
like clockwork.
-要雪茄吗？-不了 谢谢
Cigar? - No, thank you.
我...很遗憾地告诉你
I...lament to tell you this.
哈特的雇主 诺克先生
Hutter's employer, Herr Knock,
今早住进了医院
was admitted to hospital this morning.
什么
What?
你有跟他问起过托马斯吗？
Did you speak to him of Thomas?
-他疯了 -疯了？
He is mad. Mad?
精神失常
Non compos mentis.
还有 费德里希 那可怜的家伙
And, Friedrich, he...well, the wretched fellow,
尽管陷入某种宗教狂热癔症之中
while inflamed with some sort of religious mania,
但他和哈特太太念着相似的话语
he shares a similar motto to Frau Hutter:
”他要来了”
"He is coming. "
什么
What?
你到底在哪儿 托马斯
Where the devil are you, Thomas?
这让我想起了一位专家
Which brings me to the specialist.
一个叫冯-弗朗茨的人
A man by the name of von Franz.
-瑞士人 -瑞士人？
Swiss. Swiss?
阿尔宾-埃伯哈特-冯-弗朗茨教授
Professor Albin Eberhart von Franz.
也许只有他一人能诊断出她的病因
He is the sole person who may be able to diagnose her.
他是我就读苏黎世大学时
An eminent physician and scholar in Zurich
一位著名医学家 是我最好的老师
when I was at school, my finest teacher.
那就 给苏黎世发封电报吧
Send a message to Zurich, then.
不 他现在就在威斯堡
No, no, he...he's here in Wisburg.
在这儿？
Here?
就在这儿？
Here- here?
你怎么不早说伙计
Why haven't you told me, man?
-这个… -这是重要的信息
WellThis is capital news.
见鬼 伙计 你之前怎么就没想到呢
Damn it, man, why didn't you think of this before?
你知道吗 冯-弗朗茨是这个领域最权威的人
You see, he...von Franz is the most Iearned in the field,
他的智慧令人震惊
his mind staggering.
我愿意开出高价
I'll spare no expense.
不 你误解我的意思了 费德里希
No, you misunderstand me, Friedrich.
不到万不得已 我不推荐去找他
lt has fallen 德语 on me to recommend him.
他被苏黎世大学开除了
He was tossed out of the university,
被他自己祖国的国民所嘲讽驱逐
laughed out of his home country.
-什么 -这样说他我很难过但是
- What? - Grieves me to say it, but...
他一度沉迷于诸如帕拉塞尔苏斯
he became obsessed with the work of Paracelsus,
阿格里帕等人的作品
Agrippa and the like.
说点我这船夫能听懂的 西弗斯
I am a shipman, Sievers.
炼金术
Alchemy.
神秘主义
Mystic philosophy.
密教
The occult.
以上帝之名 移除这诅咒吧
让这狡猾的邪灵屈服
让它远离神圣之地
离开他 离开这里
这些上帝虚假的仆从
阿门
不 奥洛克
No! Orlok!
他生前是个黑魔法师
A black enchanter he was in life.
所罗门纳尔
Solomonar.
魔鬼保全了他的灵魂
The devil preserved his soul
使他的尸体得以再次行走在亵渎中
that his corpse may walk again in blasphemy.
你迷失在他的阴影里
You are lost in his shadow.
不 不 我得走了
No. No, I must leave.
我答应过爱伦
I promised Ellen.
留在这儿
Remain here.
他的邪恶无法进入神之殿堂
His evil cannot enter this house of God.
我答应过要回到公司
I promised I'd join the firm.
我来这里是想把威斯堡的一栋房子卖给伯爵
I came here to sell the count a house in Wisburg.
他不能离开这里
He cannot leave here.
-他要去威斯堡 -他无法离开这里
He is bound for Wisburg. He cannot leave here.
他必须回到埋葬他的
He must return to the cursed earth
那片诅咒之土地
wherein he was buried.
不 他在寻找爱伦
No! He seeks after Ellen.
我知道
I know itl
很快你见到的就不止我的阴影了
很快我们将以肉身相拥
我们将合二为一
天地间 将电闪雷鸣
而我将乘着你这野蛮之风的羽翼崛起
我没有辜负您的期望
I have not failed your lordshipl
您应许之礼物在等待着您
Thy promised gift awaits!
天意啊！
Providence!
科学界正在全力证明
The scientific community is on a crusade
他的工作已经将他逼疯
to prove his work drove him to madness.
-嗯 -我向你保证
Hmm. l assure you,
哈玎 这位教授可能有点特立独行
德语ing, the professor may be a bit unconventional,
但他会查出她的病因
but he will know the source of her malady.
冯-弗朗茨教授？
Professor von Franz?
别烦我
Leave me be.
我曾是您的学生
lt is your former student.
滚 我叫你滚啊
Avaunt! Begone, I say!
教授 拜托 我并不想打扰您
Professor, please, I should not wish to intrude.
教授 求您了
Professor, please.
我差点就能解锁
I had nearly unlocked the final key
昆氏秘典的最后一把钥匙了
of the Mysteriorum Libri Quinque.
对不起 教授
I'm sorry, Professor.
不 没关系
No. No matter.
我把星图算错了
I miscalculated the stars.
赫尔墨斯今晚不会把我的黑硫磺炼成金子了
Hermes will not render my black sulfur gold this evening.
是的 我们不会再麻烦您了
Yes, we shan't trouble you further.
-我们得走了 -等等...
We must take our leave. Just
晚上好 教授
Good night, Professor.
不要把圣物喂狗
Nolite dare sanctum canibus.
也不要把你们的珍珠丢在猪面前
Neque mittatis margaritas vestra ante porcos.
我亲爱的小西弗斯
My dear young Sievers.
还是我垂死的双眼欺骗了我
Or do my dying eyes deceive me?
我早该想到的
I should've known.
拥抱我 我的孩子
Embrace me, my boy.
见到你我倍感欣慰
I am so rejoiced to see you.
我有种预感
I sensed something.
多年前它把我带到了威斯堡
lt brought me to Wisburg all these years ago.
我感觉到它现在正在迫近
I felt it was now imminently approaching.
我以为是什么坏事 但现在看来肯定是你
I thought it ill, but it must have been you.
所以 发生了什么事？
Now, what is the matter?
啊 我明白了 是的
Ah, Isee, yes.
你的一个好朋友得了一种罕见的怪病
A dear friend of yours has some rare ailment.
也许是一个房客 对吗
Perhaps a houseguest, yes?
一位表现出
A young woman exhibiting
长期梦游症的年轻女子
protracted fits of somnambulism.
你看起来很疲劳 年轻人
You look tired, young man.
喝杜松子酒吗？
Schnapps?
等等 你还没康复！
Waitl You are not yet welll
什么事
Yeah?
快来 船长
给我回到后甲板上去
一开始是瓦西里 现在罗登科也
船长 是瘟疫 他染了瘟疫
把病人隔离起来！
真是见鬼
我们的货物被诅咒了
快躲开 快躲开
出去！所有人都出去！
立刻给这孩子松绑
Untie this child at once!
只有这样做才能不让她
lt's all I could do to keep her
把这房间弄得乱七八糟
from tearing the room to ribbons.
松绑
Untie her.
你就是西弗斯说的那个医生吗
You are the doctor our Sievers spoke of?
麻醉了
Drugged?
我一直在给她用鸦片剂
I have been administering an opiate.
她白天必须休息 因为她的身体整夜都处于
She must rest by day, for her body is in utter stress
-极度紧张状态 -她必须保持清醒
all the night. She cannot be clouded.
走开 走开
Step away. Step away.
我亲爱的可怜人 是的 我就是那医生
My dear creature, yes, I am he, and I am
我是来帮助你的
hither come to help you.
她是你的猫？
ls she yours?
格雷塔吗
Greta?
她没有男主人也没有女主人
She has no master nor mistress.
的确如此
Quite so.
请务必原谅我
I entreat you to excuse me,
我想马上开始对你的问询
but I should like to begin my consultation presently.
对你 我感到很好奇
You see, I have a curiosity about you.
西弗斯医生告诉我 你从小身上就
Dr. Sievers tells me that you have had these spells
缠着这种怪病
since childhood.
请你向我描述一下 好吗？
Would you describe them to me, please?
我不总是能记得住
I cannot always remember them.
仿佛我的灵魂已经游离了
As if my spirit wanders off.
把你能记起来的一切告诉我 从头开始
Tell me what you can, from the beginning.
曾经...现在 这就像一场梦
Sometimes it was...it is like a dream.
我能预知一些事情
And I know things.
我总能知道我的圣诞礼物盒里装的是什么
I always knew the contents of my Christmas gifts.
我知道我母亲什么时候会去世
I knew when that my mother would pass.
父亲 他会在森林中的田地里找到我
Father, he would find me in our fields within the forest
而我仿佛是个妖精小孩
as if I was his little changeling girl.
这样啊
l see.
但随着我逐渐长大 情况恶化了
But as I became older, it worsened.
我吓着他了
I frightened him.
我的触摸
My touch.
我非常孤独 你明白吗 我渴望得到安慰
I was so very alone, you see, and I wished for comfort.
接着我感觉到某种鬼怪 然后是噩梦
Then a presence and the nightmares,
癫痫随之而来 我...
the epilepsies, l
请继续说
Pray, continue.
最终 有一次爸爸发现我躺在地上
At last, Papa found me once laying.
赤身裸体
Unclothed, l was.
我的身躯 我的...
My body, my
我的肉体 我...
my flesh, l
”罪过"
"Sin. "
”罪过“他说
"Sin, "he said.
他会把我送到那个地方 我...我要不去
He would have sent me to that place. I...I shan't go.
不 不
No, no.
当我初次见到托马斯时 一切怪病都停止了
lt all ended when I first met my Thomas.
我们的爱 让我变得正常了
From our love, l became as normal.
然而 这些幻象还有梦游
Yet these visions and night wanderings
又回到了你身上？
have returned to you?
我真的好怕他
I fear for him so.
教授
Professor.
我的梦境变得越来越黑暗
My dreams grow darker.
邪恶是滋生于内心之中 还是来自彼界之外？
Does evil come from within us or from beyond?
她开始进入催眠状态了
Her trance state is begun.
你给她放血以缓解淤积了吗？
You have bled her to decrease the congestion?
当然
Of course.
她月经时也是这样吗？
And her menstruations are also?
量很大
Liberal.
太多血了 太多血了
Too much blood. Too much blood.
请拿蜡烛照个亮
A taper, please.
她的瞳孔扩散了
Her pupil is expanded.
对光没有自然的收缩反应了
lt does not contract naturally to light.
-不可能 -能预见的第二视觉
- lmpossible. A second sight.
她已经不在这里了
She is no longer here.
我的包
My bag.
请原谅接下来这一示范
Forgive the grotesque tediousness
场面可能不太好看
of this demonstration.
拿针来
The needle.
无论如何 我必须提醒诸位
However, I must impress upon you
这个孩子的意识已经不在了
that this child is not with us.
教授 我反对这样
Professor, I do protest.
收起你的反对 她现在什么也感觉不到
Restrain your protestation, for she feels nothing.
她现在正身处另一个域界
She communes now with another realm.
包扎好伤口 西弗斯
Tend to the wound, Sievers.
好了
Now...
你能听到我吗 我的孩子？
Do you hear me, my child?
你看到了什么？
And what then do you see?
我命令你 快说出你看到了什么
I charge you, speak now what you see.
漫漫长夜
Enduring night.
一个死亡的幽灵
A specter of death.
他...他蔓延开他的影子
He...he spreads his shadow,
他...他...他来了
and he...he...he is coming.
谁？谁要来找你 我的孩子？
Who? Who is coming to you, my child?
是谁 该死的 快说！
Who, damn you? Speak!
护身古符 邪祟屈服！
Yield before this ancient talisman!
教授！
Professor!
我不会伤害她的！
I will not harm herl
我命令你
I command you,
听从我的声音
hearken to my voice.
在查缪尔 哈尼尔和扎德基尔的保护下
By the protection of Chamuel, Haniel and Zadkiel,
将你所知讲述与我
impart your speech unto me.
以艾利欧格
In the name of Eligos,
奥罗巴斯和阿斯莫代的名义
Orabas and Asmoday,
将你所知讲述与我
impart your speech unto me.
我将坚持每一晚
I shall persist to join you
与你相伴 先是入睡 然后入你怀中
every night- first in sleep, then in your arms.
一切都将被
Everything will be mixed
可憎之物玷污 你将深陷于血泊之中
with abomination, and you'll be knee- deep in blood.
所有人都将恸哭
Everyone will cry.
再没有人能去埋葬死者
There will be none to bury the dead.
-你被许配给我了！-什么许配？
You are promised to mel- Promised?
-她说的是她的丈夫！-答应了什么？
She means her husbandl- Promised?
救我！救救我！
Help me! Help mel
正如我所担心的
As I feared.
然后呢？
Well?
”然后”什么 孩子 你难道不明白吗？
"Well"what, my boy? Cannot you see?
明白什么？
See what?
她这是被诅咒了
See that she is cursed.
-诅咒了？-是的 被诅咒了
Cursed? - Yes, cursed.
这个可怜的孩子被某种恶灵附身了
This dear young creature is possessed of some spirit.
也许是个恶魔
Perhaps a demon.
您说什么呢
I beg your pardon.
我向你保证 哈玎
I assure you, 德语ing,
教授这样说是一种比喻
the professor means this as hyperbole.
-不 我说的就是恶魔 -你在开玩笑吧
No, Imean a demon. You jest.
但你自己的那些关于
But what of your own discoveries
恐怖幻觉的病理学发现呢？
of macabre hallucination pathologies?
这次不一样
This is not one.
你不能单凭感觉就认定这一切
You cannot conceivably have perceived all of this.
这怎么会发生在爱伦身上？
How should this happen to Ellen?
恶魔邪灵更容易迷惑那些
Demonic spirits more easily obsess those
被低级动物功能占主导地位的人
whose lower animal functions dominate.
恶魔喜欢他们 它们寻找他们
Demons like them. They seek them out.
我不愿与您争辩 教授
I do not wish to dispute you, Professor,
但我自己就亲眼见过神经脆弱的女人
but I myself have witnessed women of nervous constitutions
编造出各种各样的幻觉
invent all manner of delusion.
这不是幻觉
This is no delusion.
我相信她一直对这些宇宙的力量
I believe she has always been highly conductive
高度敏感 而且是独一无二的
to these cosmic forces, uniquely so.
也许在你眼里 是疯子
Your lunatic, perhaps.
那么你承认这些病例之间有联系吗？
Do you then acknowledge a connection between these cases?
这就是问题所在
That is the question.
真是好极了
Oh, this is just capital.
我告诉你 这都是她丈夫失踪造成的
I tell you, it is the manner of her husband's disappearance.
不 这邪灵…
No. This evil- -
它是什么 它是如何被召唤
what it is, how it has been summoned,
如何被释放的 我不清楚
unleashed, l know not,
但这个被它紧抓不放的 非凡的孩子
but this remarkable child it has chained itself to
正身处重大危险之中
is in grave peril.
我必须回书房去
I must to my studies.
哈玎太太
Frau 德语ing.
陪她待在一起 观察她
Sit with her. Observe her.
报告她的行为
Report her behavior.
西弗斯 不要再用乙醚了
Sievers, no more ether.
但她会一整晚发狂的
But she will rave all the night.
那就让她发一整晚的狂
Then rave she must.
一场可怕的风暴即将到来
There is a dread storm rising.
我会结束这场瘟疫 这个恶魔
-救救我 救救我！-噢 我的天
Help me. Help mel- Oh, dear. Oh, my.
我救你出来
I'lI get you out.
别担心
Don't you worry.
救命
Help.
没关系 没关系
lt's all right. lt's all right.
-听 -你说什么？
Listen. What was that?
听
Listen.
尊敬的大人...他来了！
His lordship- he has comel
鲜血就是生命
The blood is the life.
他来了 他来了！
He's here. He's here!
大人他来了！
His lordship is herel
鲜血就是生命！
The blood is the lifel
他来了！
He's here!
爱伦？
Ellen?
托马斯！
Thomas!
不 不！
No, no!
托马斯！
Thomas!
托马斯
Thomas.
他还没找到你
He hasn't found you.
我...我好怕再也见不到你了
I- I feared I'd never see you again.
我亲爱的
My love.
你是对的
You were right.
You were.
他...他拿了你的吊坠
He he has your locket.
托马斯
Thomas.
现在又怎么了？
What the hell is it now?
-托马斯！-哈特曼开门！
Thomasl- Hartmann, the doorl
是的 先生
Very good, sir.
托马斯！
Thomas!
妈妈！爸爸！
Mamal Papa!
是怪物吗？
ls that the monster?
到底是什么事？
What the devil is this?
现在都凌晨三点多了
lt's past 3: 00 in the morning.
上帝啊
My God.
瘟疫 这是一艘瘟疫船
Plague. lt's a plague ship.
该死
Damn it.
通知港口当局
Alert the port authority.
-去找西弗斯医生来 -遵命 长官
And fetch Dr. Sievers. Aye, aye, sir.
他来啦 大人
There it is, your lordship.
他来啦
There it is.
那经纪人还活着
The broker lives.
我会让那新郎闭嘴的 大人
I shall stifle out the bridegroom, your lordship.
他对我还有用处
I have use in him.
拜托…
Pray
请指明
lnstruct me.
命令我 利用我
Charge me. Use me.
我会给您带来
I shall fetch unto thee
您漂亮的所有物
thy pretty belonging
契约规定
The compact commands
她必须自愿重新起誓
she must willingly repledge her vow.
她不能被强夺
She cannot be stolen.
然而 大人...
Yet, my lord
我乞 求您...
I beg thee...
住嘴 畜生
Silence, dogl
你的恳求变得放肆了
Your entreaties grow insolent.
你没有向我索求的资格
You shall crave of me nothing.
大人
My lord.
快要破晓了
Daybreak draws near.
不久 黎明的钟声
Anon, the bells of dawn
将为我的到来而绝望地敲响
shall toll in despair of my coming.
我将品尝尔等滋味
And I shall taste of you.
他怎么样了？
How is he faring
恐怕不比大家口中我的遭遇更好
I fear no better than everyone tells me I have suffered.
请原谅我给你带来的所有麻烦
Pray, forgive me for all the troubles I have caused you.
我很高兴你又恢复了自我
I am only glad you have become yourself again.
这简直是个奇迹
lt seems a miracle.
也许弗朗茨教授错了
Perhaps Professor Franz was wrong.
也许这只是你希望托马斯回来
Perhaps it was only your wish to see Thomas returned
和你的...你的...
and your...your
我的忧郁症
My melancholy
-我... -托马斯看到了
Uh, l. Thomas has seen
一些可怕的东西
something awful.
要是我能和教授说说...
lf only I could speak to the profess
不要 他的想法很奇怪
Hush. His thoughts are so queer.
弗朗茨教授说是个恶魔
Professor Franz said a demon.
伦儿 求求你
Leni, please.
看在孩子们的份上
For the sake of the children.
圣诞节快到了
Christmastide is upon us.
你为什么总是这么固执己见？
Why must you remain so exasperatingly contrary
因为我是对的
Because I am in the right.
西弗斯 我想要见的
Sievers, I requested conference
是你的疯人 不是一个死人
with your maniac, not a dead man.
教授 请您耐心一点 但这正是让我烦恼的事
I beg your patience, Professor, but this is what vexes me.
他表现出所有血疫的迹象
He exhibits all the signs of a blood plague
败血症 眼部分泌物
Sepsis, ophthalmic discharge.
甚至这里和这里被啮齿动物明显咬过
Even flagrant rodent bites here and here.
恐怕这艘船已经把瘟疫带进了威斯堡
I fear this ship has brought the plague to Wisburg.
令人困惑的是
And what is confounding is
他的身体里完全没有血液
his body is entirely absent of blood.
看看这里这个奇怪的伤口
Look at this curious mark here.
我在这的运河里 见过像利维坦一样巨大的害兽
I've seen some leviathan- like pests in our canals,
但告诉我 教授 什么老鼠有这么大的下颚？
but tell me, Professor, what rat has jaws of such size
天使和恶魔保佑
Angels and demons protect us.
你那个疯子在哪？
Where is your lunatic
你必须马上带我去见他
You must take me to him presently.
医生 你没听说吗？
Ain't you heard, Doctor, sir
没有
No.
诺克先生逃走不见了
Herr Knock has gone and escaped.
什么？
What
他昨晚杀了值班的门房
He killed the porter on duty last night.
必须找到这个人
This man must be found.
伙计 带我出去
Sirrah, show me out.
西弗斯 去叫哈玎
Sievers, fetch 德语ing.
今晚到我家碰头
And meet me at my residence tonight.
这不是瘟疫那么简单
This is no mere plague.
放开我
Get off me.
给我点空间
Give me room.
托马斯
Thomas.
-我喘不过气 -是我
- I- lcan't breathe. - lt's me.
我喘不过气
I- l can't breathe.
滚开！
Get offl
求求你 妈妈 不要离开我们
Please you, don't leave us, Mama.
我保证不会让任何东西伤害你们
I promise I shan't let anything harm you.
怪物不行 什么都不行
No monsters. Nothing.
好了 亲我一下
Now, give me a kiss.
然后念你们的祷词
And say your prayers.
现在我就要躺下睡觉
Now I lay me down to sleep,
祈祷主将我的灵魂照料
I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
安娜
Anna
噢 你吓到我了
Oh. Oh, you frightened me.
请原谅
Forgive me.
费德里希回来了吗？
Has Friedrich returned
呃 还没有
Uh, uh, no. No
怎么了 我亲爱的？
What is it, my lovely
我可以...
May I
今晚和你待在一起吗？
stay with you tonight
我们的友谊是我心灵的珍贵慰藉
Our friendship is a precious balm to my heart.
请原谅我总责备你
Forgive my chiding you.
感谢你一直爱我
Thank you for loving me.
你想要可以拿走
You may take it if you wish.
上帝与我们同在 伦儿
God is with us, Leni.
我不能认同这是鬼魂的侵扰
I cannot yield to being haunted by a ghost.
噢不 才不是呢
Oh, no, please. No
它才不是鬼魂 它能以实体形式出现
lt is no mere ghost, for it can manifest physically
而且心怀最邪恶的意图
and with the most foul intent.
那请问 究竟是什么意图？
And what, pray, is that
像所有的瘟疫一样 它的本性渴望
Like every plague, its soul desire
就是要吞噬世界上所有的生命
is to consume all life on Earth.
这个生物的力量比邪恶还要强大
This creature is a force more powerful than evil.
它就是死亡本身
lt is Death itself.
我已经好几天没睡了
I have not slept in days.
我的家变得混乱不堪
My house has become a bedlam,
而我又被叫到这里
and here I've been resummoned
这个上帝遗弃的地方听这种鬼话
to this godforsaken habitation for this
别告诉我你相信这种中世纪的妖魔鬼怪！
Do not tell me you believe in such medieval devilry!
我不是相信 我是知道！
I do not believe. I know!
我在这个世界上见过的事情
I have seen things in this world
会让艾萨克-牛顿
that would've made lsaac Newton crawl
爬回他母亲的子宫
back into his mother's womb.
我们并没有变得多么开明
We have not become so much enlightened
而是被科学的虚幻光芒蒙蔽了双眼
as we have been blinded by the gaseous light of science.
我亲身与魔鬼搏斗过
I have wrestled with the devil
就像雅各在毗努伊勒与天使摔跤一样
as Jacob wrestled the angel in Peniel.
我告诉你 如果我们想要驯服黑暗
And I tell you, if we are to tame darkness,
我们必须先承认黑暗的存在
we must first face that it exists.
诸位先生
Meine Herren,
我们这是遇到了 传播瘟疫的不死者
we are here encountering the undead plague carrier,
吸血鬼诺斯费拉图
the Vampyr Nosferatu.
你
You.
我感觉到你
I have felt you
像毒蛇一样在我体内爬行
crawling like a serpent in my body.
那不是我
lt is not me.
那是你的本性
lt is your nature.
不 我爱托马斯
No. I love Thomas.
爱对你来说是次等的
Love is inferior to you.
我告诉过你 你并非人类
I told you, you are not of humankind.
你这么说太恶毒了
You are a villain to speak so.
我只是胃口好
I am an appetite.
仅此而已
Nothing more.
数个世纪来 一头令人厌恶的野兽
O'er centuries, a loathsome beast
我一直躺在最黑暗的深坑里
I lay within the darkest pit.
直到你唤醒了我 女法师
Till you did wake me, enchantress,
搅醒了我的墓中之梦
and stirred me from my grave.
你是我的灾祸
You are my affliction.
我才不管你的灾祸呢
I care nothing of your afflictions.
但即便如此 我们是命中注定
Yet even now we are fated.
你的丈夫签下了自己的名字
Your husband has signed his name
将你许配给我
and covenanted you to my person
只为换取一袋黄金
for but a sack of gold.
-这是谎言 -为了黄金
Lies. For gold,
他解除了婚姻的纽带
he did absolve his nuptial bond.
你对他一无所知
You know nothing of him.
而婚约的解除 必须由你来完成
And the resignation must be completed by you
是你完全自愿的
freely of thine own will.
你就是个欺骗者
You are a deceiver.
是你在自欺欺人
You deceive yourself.
我当时不过是个天真的孩子
I was but an innocent child.
所以你就认为我不会回来了吗？
And thought you I would not return?
你以为我不来找你了吗？
Thought you I would not?
你的激情与我紧密联结
Your passion is bound to me.
你无法去爱
You cannot love.
我不能
l cannot.
可是没有你我就得不到满足
Yet I cannot be sated without you.
还记得我们曾经的日子吗？
Remember how once we were?
还记得任何片段吗？
A moment. Remember?
我对你深恶痛绝
I abhor you.
你在胡说！
You are false!
所以你也想看我证明我的敌意吗？
So you wish me to prove my enmity as well?
我会给你三个晚上
I will leave you three nights.
今晚是第一晚
Tonight was the first.
今晚你矢口否认
Tonight you denied yourself,
因此 我要让你
and thereby, you suffer me
看着所爱之人生命消逝而受到折磨
to vanish up the lives of those you love.
说我矢口否认？
Denied myself?
你沉醉于对我的折磨
You revel in my torture.
等到第三天晚上 你必须顺从与我
Upon the third night, you will submit,
否则 你那所谓的丈夫
or he you call your husband
将殒命于我手
shall perish by my hand.
不
No.
等到你请我过来
Till you bid me come
你就会眼睁睁看着世界化为乌有
shall you watch the world become as naught.
不
No!
还有两个晚上
我从来没见过这样的东西
I ain't never seen the like.
从昨天早上开始 它的传播速度比野火还快
lt's been a- spreading faster than wildfire since yestermorn.
我们无法接收更多病人了
We simply cannot admit any more.
传播速度太快了
The contraction rate is too high.
我已经恳请市长施行隔离
I've entreated the burgomaster for a quarantine.
-必须封锁这座城市 -这样有悖基督教义
The city must be shut up. - lt ain't Christian.
我们会腾出空间的 先生
We can find rooms, sir.
审判日就要到了 先生 发发慈悲
The day of judgment's a- coming, sir. Take pity.
面对这场瘟疫 我们必须保持冷静
We must remain calm in the face of this plague.
一片阴影逼近
A shadow pressing.
我的身体在下沉
My body sinking.
下沉
Sinking.
腐肉的恶臭
The smell of rancid meat.
令人窒息
Suffocating.
我
I...
我感觉很虚弱
I feel so weak. l...
我担心小费德里希长得太强壮
I fear little Friedrich is so strong,
饿到把我整个吃空
so hungry he is eating me weary.
我可以 我可以看看女儿们吗？
May I...may I see the girls?
我必须跟她们保证
I must assure them
一切都会没事的 亲爱的
Everything will be well, my darling.
一切都会好起来的
Everything shall be just fine.
我自己都不清楚
I don't know myself.
爱伦 告诉我
Ellen, tell me,
这难以忍受的黑暗是什么？
what is this insufferable darkness?
我
I.
哈玎先生 你一定要听我说
Herr 德语ing, you must see me.
有一些存在
There is something.
一种阴影 地狱般的生物
The shadow, an infernal creature.
-爱伦 -拜托
Ellen. Please!
这不是精神疾病
These are no troubled nerves.
这就是弗朗茨教授形容的那样 一个恶魔
It is as Professor Franz described- a demon.
哈特太太 请原谅 但我要你和托马斯
Frau Hutter, forgive me, but I need you and Thomas-
你们两人 回家去
both of you- to return home.
什么
What?
这是为了你们着想
lt's for your own sake
求你了
Please.
发发慈悲 托马斯身体还很差
Have pity. Thomas is very poorly.
我不知道我该怎么...
I know not what I
我会为汤姆祈祷的
I shall pray for Tom
-你知道我是爱你们的 -安娜呢
- You know I love you both. What of Anna?
你没看到她吗
Did you not see her?
那不关你的事
lt's none of your concern.
费德里希 你必须听我说
Friedrich, you must listen to me
我们都处于极大的危险之中
We're all in the most grave danger.
我把我自己送到你的面前
I throw myself at your feet!
哈特夫人 拜托
Frau Hutter, please!
你为什么恨我？
Why do you hate me?
你怎么敢用这种方式跟我说话
How dare you speak to me in that marked manner?
你从未喜欢过我 从来没有
You have never liked me. Never.
认清自己的位置 女士
Know your place, madam.
我不会袖手旁观 假装你的高高在上
I will not stand by and pretend at your superiority.
我不想跟你
I refuse to exchange
-相互指责 -为什么你不听我的话呢
reproaches with you. - Why can you not hear me?
听我说 求求你！
Listen to me, pleasel
在这漫长的几个月里
I have done everything in my power
我尽自己所能地向你表达善意
to be kind to you in these long months.
把我绑起来吗
Tied me up.
给自己留点尊严 对照顾你的人表示敬意
Find the dignity to display the respect to your caretaker.
你怎么能如此愚蠢和残忍？
How can you be so stupid and cruel?
哈特曼会给你们找一辆马车
Hartmann will call you a coach.
当然 费用由我承担
My expense, of course.
看在你丈夫的份上 我祈求你去学学
And for your husband's sake, I pray you learn
行为举止如何能更自重一点
to conduct yourself with more deference.
安娜就要死了
Anna is going to die.
你也要死了
You are going to die!
我们都要死了
We're all going to diel
之前你为什么没有告诉我？
Why did you not tell me of this before?
我真是傻瓜
I am a fool.
当然是诺克先生
Of course it is Herr Knock.
以他对生吞活物的痴迷
His obsessive consumption of living creatures-
一定就是他
it must be him.
他不是诺斯费拉图
He is not Nosferatu.
但必须抓到他
But he must be found,
因为他已经与这阴影缔约
for he has made compact with this shadow.
搜查所有地方
Search everything.
把地毯掀起来
Pull up the rug.
所罗门那利
Solomonari.
还有他们的秘密法典
And their codex of secrets.
”我站在海边的沙滩上”
"Then I stood on the sand by the sea.
”我看见一头怪兽从海中浮出水面”
"And I saw a beast rising out of the sea.
”巨蟒将权力交接给了怪兽”
"And the serpent gave the beast authority
”亵渎伟大之名”
"...to speak of great names in blasphemy.
”那怪兽形似斑豹”
"And the beast had the form of a leopard,
”脚如熊掌 口若雄狮”
"the feet of a bear, the mouth of a lion!
”那怪兽有七个头十只角”
"A beast with seven heads and ten hornsl
”每只角上都戴着一顶王冠”
"On each horn a crown,
”每个头上都有一个亵渎之名”
on each head a blasphemous name..."
我们的梦游者和她的丈夫
Our somnambulist and her husband
正处于极大的危险之中
are in incomparable danger.
我必须见到他们
I must see them.
我让他们回家去了
I sent them home.
怎样才能杀死这个变态者
How can this perversion be killed?
我不知道 你送他们回家了吗
I do not know. You sent them home?
-什么 -你送他们回家了吗
What? - You sent them home?
没有 不对 是的 我送了
No, not that. Yes, I did.
你居然不知道？
You don't know?
没错 正确
Precisely. Correct.
我不知道
I do not know.
我从未亲眼见过诺斯费拉图
I have never encountered Nosferatu firsthand.
他不知道
He doesn't know.
你那些高深造作的文字
AlI your fine lectures are mere regurgitations
不过是纸上谈兵！
from bloody books!
对于阻止与毁灭它的方式
The means of repelling and destroying
每个地区之间都大有不同
vary greatly from region to region.
效果显然是未知的
Their efficacy is plainly unknown.
不过 有一个不变的事实
Yet there is one invariable fact
-最让我感兴趣 -继续说
that interests me most. Go on.
无论如何 诺斯费拉图都必须
ln every account, the Nosferatu must return
在第一声鸡鸣响起时
to the earth wherein it was buried
回到埋葬它的大地
by first crow of cock.
它白天必须沉睡在坟墓之中
lt must sleep in its grave by day.
如果没回去会怎样
What happens if it does not?
亲爱的西弗斯 这就是问题所在
That, my dear Sievers, is the question.
天啊
Oh, God.
我的天
My God.
我浑身颤抖
I am shattering.
我快要四分五裂 出去
I'm breaking apart. Get out.
-哈玎 -立刻离开这里
Har- 德语ing. Take your leave at once.
你们两个
Both of you!
费德里希 拜托 我们不希望
Friedrich, please, we do not wish to
先生们 难道你们看不见一场真正的瘟疫吗
Can't you see there's a bloody real plague, gentlemen?
活生生的人正被一场实在的流行病杀死
A real epidemic that is really killing real people.
-该死的 哈玎 -噢 你们两个
Damn you, 德语ingl Oh, the pair of youl
很抱歉 西弗斯 我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Sievers. l'm sorry.
哈特女士已经疯了
Frau Hutter is mad
而且很早就该被关起来了
and should have been locked up long ago.
我的安娜
My Anna
是被害兽给咬了
was bitten by vermin.
老鼠罢了
Ratsl No more.
明日 我们启程离开威斯堡
Tomorrow, we are leaving Wisburg.
但有疫情 明日这里就封城了
But the quarantine- tomorrow, we close off the city.
我不会允许你徒劳的疯狂杀死我妻子
I'm not gonna let your vain madness kill my wife.
那夜魔已经吸过你妻子的鲜血
The night demon has supped of your good wife's blood
必定会回来索取剩下的
and shall return for the rest.
走吧
Leave.
噢 托马斯
Oh, Thomas.
爱伦 我亲爱的
Ellen, my love.
我们必须离开了
We must go.
我们必须逃离城市
We must flee the city.
你现在很危险
You're in danger.
-你知道... -我们不能逃走
You knew We cannot run.
不 我们必须走
No, we must.
有些事我必须告诉你
There is something I must tell you.
有些过于可憎 过于卑鄙的事
Something so loathsome, so base.
无论你说什么 都无法让我动摇
Nothing you can say will shake me,
这世界上存在邪魔
for there is a devil in this world,
而我已经亲自见过他 他…
and I have met him, and he...
我无从开口说起 他
I cannot speak it. He
他来威斯堡就是要找你
He is come to Wisburg for you.
我知道
l know.
什么？
What?
我认识他
I know him.
认识他？
Know him?
是我将这邪魔引来的
I've brought this evil upon us.
我从未跟任何人
I have never shared my
分享过我的秘密
secret with any soul.
我曾渴望陪伴
I sought company.
我曾渴望...
l sought.
温柔 于是我日日呼唤
tenderness, and I called out.
-你这是什么意思 -起初 它如此甜美
- What do you mean by this? - At first, it was sweet.
-我从未感受过如此欣喜 -爱伦
- I had never known such bliss. Ellen.
但后来这变成了折磨
Yet it turned to torture.
简直要了我的命
lt would kill me.
但托马斯
But, Thomas
是你给了我脱离这些羞耻的勇气
it was you that gave me the courage to be free of my shame.
是你
You.
你这是在说什么
What are you telling me?
你不明白吗？
Don't you understand?
拜托 请让我明白
Pray, help me to.
他就是我的羞耻 他就是我的忧郁症
He is my shame. He is my melancholy.
他那时认我做他的情人 现在他回来了
He took me as his lover then, and now he has come back.
他发现我们结婚了 于是他回来了
He has discovered our marriage and has come back.
不可能
lmpossible.
他在我梦中纠缠我
He stalks me in my dreams.
我每夜的睡梦中都只能想着他
AlI my sleeping thoughts are of him every night.
-爱伦 -别碰我
Ellen. Don't touch me!
我不应该被触碰
I am not to be touched.
你之前不再给我写信了
You stopped your letters to me.
什么？
What?
你向我保证要每天写信给我
You promised to write to me every day.
你在城堡里时不再想着我了吗
Did not you think of me in that castle?
我想了 我
Idid. l...
说谎
Lies.
你刚向我坦白了那些 你怎么敢
After what you have just confessed, how
他跟我说到过你
He told me about you.
他告诉我你有多么愚蠢
He told me how foolish you were.
多么担惊受怕
How fearful.
像个孩子一样
How like a child.
你投向他的怀抱就像女人手中的百合
How you fell into his arms as a swooning lily of a woman.
爱伦
Ellen.
他告诉我你把我卖给他换取金子
He told me how you sold me to him for gold.
-不 我 -我们的爱本应是神圣的
No, IOur love was supposed to be sacredl
-爱伦 拜托 -你从不听我说话
Ellen, please. You never listen!
它在哪呢？
Well, where is it?
你的钱呢？你的仕途 你的宅邸呢？
Your money? Your promotion? Your house?
对你来说如此珍贵的东西在哪里？
Where is that which is so precious to you?
你欠哈玎的债都还清了吗
Have you paid back kind 德语ing your debt?
难道你用这场传染了他妻子的瘟疫来回报他吗？
Have you repaid him with this plague that infects his wife?
我是为了我们的未来才离家
I left for us, for our future.
为了什么？为了什么？就为了这些物什？
For what? For what? For these thingsl
-为了你啊！-这无所谓了
For youl lt doesn't matterl
无所谓了
lt doesn't matt
你不明白吗
Can't you see?
我们就不该结婚
We should never have married
我们早已是行尸走肉
We're already deadl
爱伦 拜托
Ellen, please.
爱伦
Ellen!
我 我去找西弗斯医生
I- Ishall send for Dr. Sievers.
不
No!
不要 求求你
No! Please, please.
我会好好的
I'll be good.
我会好好的 我保证 我保证
I'lI be good. I promise. I promise.
你永远无法像他那样满足我
You could never please me as he could.
没错 占有我！
Yes! Take me!
求求你
Please.
Please!
没错
Yes!
吻我
Kiss me.
亲吻我的心 我的心
Kiss my heart. My heart.
让他看 让他看看我们的爱
Let him see. Let him see our love.
没有你 我将成为恶魔
Without you, l will become a demon.
爱伦 爱伦 爱伦
Ellen. Ellen! Ellen!
爱伦 是我啊 爱伦
Ellen, it's me. Ellen.
爱伦 我爱你 我爱你
Ellen, I love you. I love you.
你跟我一起很安全
You're safe with me.
是我啊 是我啊
lt's me. lt's me.
不要接近我 我是不洁的
Keep away from me. I am unclean.
绝不
Never.
如果我不去找他 他会杀了你
He will murder you if I do not go to him.
我们会阴阳两隔 世界将是一片绝望
We will be torn apart, and the world will be despair.
不
No.
我会杀了他
I'II kill him.
我一定要杀了他
Kill him I will.
他绝不能再伤害你
He shall never harm you again.
绝不
Never.
终于
At last.
“看那 美丽的姑娘”
"And lo, the maiden fair
”将她的爱献上给那野兽”
"did offer up her love unto the beast
”与他依偎相拥”
"and with him lay in close embrace
”直到鸡鸣破晓”
"until the first cock crow.
”她的献身就此打破了诅咒”
"Her willing sacrifice thus broke the curse
”从此他们不再受诺斯费拉图瘟疫的侵扰”
and freed them from the plague of Nosferatu. "
她就是方法
She is the way.
不要醒来
爸爸 爸爸
Papa! Papa!
费德里希 费德里希
Friedrich. Friedrich!
费德里希 醒醒
Friedrich, wake up.
我不能再哭泣了 我的泪已经哭干
I can weep no longer, for I have no more tears to shed.
我们必须同他谈谈
We must speak with him.
再等一下吧 他现在悲痛欲绝
Just a moment longer. His grief is too great.
借一步说话？
May I?
还会有更多人被害
More will be taken.
-她还有身孕 -我知道
She was with child. - l know.
死神随着风向的变动
The grim reaper wields his heavy scythe
挥动他那沉重的镰刀
with every change of wind.
教授 我必须跟您谈谈
Professor, I must speak with you.
我也要找你谈谈
And I would speak with you.
快把那混蛋从这赶走！
Take that blackguard from this place!
-你那病态的内心... -拜托 拜托
Your diseased mind Please. Please.
...导致了现在这些肆虐
...has brought all of this outrage!
-快住手 -住手 求求你 这是我的错
Stop this. Stop, please. lt is my fault.
现在的问题跟你没有关系 托马斯
This moment doesn't concern you, Thomas.
-光是看到你在场... -你的恐惧撕碎了我们的心
Your very presence... Your horror has rent our hearts,
-但你必须听我们讲 -就让我厌恶
but you must hear us. does me wrong!
费德里希 这些梦魇是真实的
Friedrich, these nightmares do existl
它们真实存在
They exist.
而他完全没有患血疾的迹象
And yet he shows no sign of the blood plague.
好修女们想要
The good sisters sought to nurse me
靠她们的祈祷助我康复
back to health with their prayer,
但我恐怕还未逃脱他的魔咒
yet I fear I'm not free of his spell.
相信上帝 还有你自己的力量
Trust in God and your strength.
怪物将你丢给狼群 然而你存活了下来
The monster left you to the wolves, yet you prevailed.
哈玎
德语ing.
原谅我 我之前很失态我
Forgive me. I'm not myself. l
请原谅我吧 大家
Please forgive me, all of you.
我的个中原因无法令人接受
My reason could not accept...accept
力量 要有力量
Strength, man. Strength.
奥洛克把棺材保存在格吕内瓦尔德庄园里吗
Orlok has kept his coffin within Grunewald Manor?
-绝对是的 -就在我们鼻子底下
Assuredly. Under our very noses.
今晚 我们要杀死那野兽
Tonight, we destroy the beast.
-让我跟你们一起去 -当然不行 爱伦
Let me come with you. No, of course not, Ellen.
你必须待在安全的地方
You must be kept safe away.
我们在哈玎家碰头 再出发去庄园
We shall meet at 德语ing's and depart for the manor.
拜托一切准备就绪了
Please. The readiness is all.
我们会圣化他埋葬的土地
We shall sanctify the earth wherein he is buried
并毁掉石棺
and destroy the sarcophagus.
这样在破晓时 他就无处遁藏了
Then he can have no sanctuary at cock crow.
当我们发现尸体时呢
And when we uncover the body?
我会将冰冷的铁锥刺穿他的身体
I will drive a spike of cold iron through him.
-如果没有作用呢 -必须起作用
- What if it does not work? - lt must.
教授 请让我送您到门口
Professor, allow me to walk you to your door.
我知道 必须是我来 教授
l know...it must be me, Professor.
在神秘学领域 我不过是略知皮毛
I am but an able tourist in this occult world
你则有天生的能力
You were born to it.
这是个罕见的天赋
lt is a rare gift.
他对我的吸引是如此强大
His pull to me is so powerful,
如此可怕
so terrible,
然而我的灵魂无法与他一样邪恶
yet my spirit cannot be evil as his.
想要摧毁邪恶 我们必须先了解邪恶
We must know evil to be able to destroy it.
我们必须在我们自身中找到邪恶
We must discover it within ourselves.
然后 我们必须将自身的邪恶钉死
And when we have, we must crucify the evil within us,
不然就没有救赎可言了
or there is no salvation.
我不需要救赎
I need no salvation.
我这一生 不过是顺从了我的天性
My entire life, I have done no ill but heed my nature.
那就仔细倾听
Then hearken to it.
恐怕 诺斯费拉图并不怕任何铁锥刺穿
I fear Nosferatu is impervious to any of our iron stakes.
我相信只有你
I'm convinced only you
才有能力拯救我们
have the faculty to redeem us.
爱伦 我们快点
Ellen, let us make haste.
在异教的时代
ln heathen times,
你也许能当上伊西斯的女大祭司
you might have been a great priestess of lsis.
但在这个陌生的现代世界
Yet, in this strange and modern world,
你的作用应该有更大的价值
your purpose is of greater worth.
你就是我们的救赎
You are our salvation.
谢谢你
Thank you.
今晚我会引开你的丈夫
I will keep your husband at bay tonight.
去吧 回家去
Go now. Go home.
确保他的身体状况可以参与这场无谓的追捕
Attend him that he is sturdy for this false hunt.
你会让这一切结束吧
You will put an end to all of this?
向我保证 杀死他之前不要回来
Promise you shan't return to me till he is no more.
-保证之后你才会回来 -我保证
Promise me you won't return. I promise.
他没有控制你的力量 托马斯
He does not have power over you, Thomas.
我全身心地信任你
I place my utter faith in you.
我爱你
I love you.
不要害怕
Fear not.
再见了
Goodbye.
他不在这吗？
He is not here?
不 哈玎先生已经走了 先生
No, Mr. 德语ing has departed, sir.
他能去哪呢
Where could he have gone?
他现在悲痛万分
He has a heavy grief.
我们应该等等他
We shall wait for him.
日落之前还有时间
There's time yet till sundown.
不 我们必须找到他
No, we must find him.
他现在状态不好 西弗斯 我为他担心
He is unwell, Sievers. I fear for him.
-哈玎 -哈玎
德语ingl 德语ingl
费德里希
Friedrich!
克拉拉
Clara.
露易丝
Louise.
我的女儿们
Oh, my girls.
安娜
Anna.
你的床一片漆黑
Your bed is so dark.
这么小
So small.
安娜 我亲爱的
Anna, my love.
我们的儿子
Our son.
我们的小儿子
Our little son.
原谅我
Forgive me.
我将永不再入睡
I shall never sleep again.
永不
Never.
让这 你这温柔的怀抱
Let this, your tender embrace,
让我感受欣喜
keep me now in bliss,
从这无尽的长眠中醒来
away from everlasting sleep.
费德里希
Friedrich!
上帝啊
Oh, God.
我们太晚了
We are too late.
我们必须烧掉他们染了病的尸体
We must set fire to their infected bodies.
我们的火焰会净化他们
Our flames will sanctify them.
我再也受不了了
I cannot bear any more.
拜托 我们必须继续了
Please, we must onward.
但奥洛克 他现在应该已经醒了吧
But Orlok- will he not already have risen?
我们是不是应该回去？
Should we not return to our homes?
不 我不能等到早上
No, I will not wait til morning.
很明智 年轻的托马斯
Very wise, young Thomas.
今夜我感觉到他对我的压制
I feel his hold upon me this night.
愿上帝宽恕他们的灵魂
May God have mercy on their souls.
”以耶和华之名”
"ln the Name of Jehovah,
”以这三圣名的力量与威严n
"and by the power and dignity of these three Names,
”四字神名 六字神名 原始神名”
"Tetragrammaton, Anexhexeton, Primematum,
”放逐你 忤逆之灵诺斯费拉图”
"cast thee, O thou disobedient Spirit Nosferatu,
”去往烈火湖泊”
"into the Lake of Fire,
”直到毁灭之日”
"there to remain until the Day of Doom
”在来审判活人死人上帝面前”
"and not to be remembered before the face of God
”被众人遗忘”
"who shall come to judge the quick and the dead
”世界熊熊燃烧”
and the world with fire. "
看啊 第三个晚上了
院子外有座小教堂
There is a chapel beyond the courtyard.
快去 托马斯
Make haste, Thomasl
我准备好了
I am ready.
我请你 来我身边
I bid you, come to me.
他在那
There he lies.
噢 上帝
Oh, God.
去吧 托马斯
Go forward, Thomas.
让恶魔的肉体得到解脱
Set free the demon's body.
托马斯 不要
Thomas, no!
诺克先生
Herr Knock.
我
l
将我的灵魂交由给他
relinquished him my soul.
我本应是群鼠的王子 永生不死
I should have been the Prince of Rats, immortal.
但他只在乎他那漂亮的新娘
But he cares only for his pretty bride,
-她对他也是 -不可置信
- and she is his. Monstrous.
再来一次
Strike again.
我即渎神
I am blasphemy.
去死吧 你这受诅的地狱畸胎
Die, you accursed mis- birth of hell!
放火烧掉一切
Set fire to it all.
该死的 他去找我妻子了
Damn it, man, he has gone to my wife.
我们必须烧了它
We must burn it.
我们必须摧毁他所有的巢穴
We must destroy all his habitation.
一处不留
No sanctuary.
不 没有时间可以浪费了
No, there is no time to be lost.
-他去追爱伦了 -这非她不可
He pursues Ellen. - lt must be herl
他无法抗拒她的鲜血
He cannot resist her blood!
你真是疯了
You are a madman.
你知道奥洛克不会在这里
You knew Orlok would not be here.
你从今天下午就知道了
You knew it this afternoon.
这是你妻子的意思
Your wife wills it.
这真是不道德！
This is not morall
上帝已经远超我们的道德
God is beyond our morals!
没用的 没用的 你的追逐是无用的
ln vain! ln vain! You run in vain!
你无法追上她的命运
You cannot outrun her destinyl
她与那野兽的黑暗联结能救赎我们所有人
Her dark bond with the beast shall redeem us all,
当太阳纯洁的光辉刺破清晨
for when the sun's pure light shall break upon the dawn,
救赎将至
redemption!
瘟疫将会消失
The plague shall be lifted!
救赎将至
Redemption!
你自愿接受这一切吗？
我愿意
l do.
那么契约就此履行
你再次起誓
是的
Yes.
你再次起誓
我们也将再次结合
你是我的
再来
More.
爱伦
Ellen.
原谅我们
Forgive us.
”看那 美丽的姑娘”
"And lo, the maiden fair
”将她的爱献上给那野兽”
"did offer up her love unto the beast
”与他依偎相拥”
"and with him lay in close embrace
”直到鸡鸣破晓”
"until the first cock crow.
”她的献身就此打破了诅咒”
"Her wllling sacrifice thus broke the curse
”从此他们不再受诺斯费拉图瘟疫的侵扰”
and freed them from the plague of Nosferatu. "